Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم الإدارة، شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
=Phoenix's Homecoming=
=عودة فينيكس إلى الوطن=
=Episode 21=
=الحلقة ٢١=
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
Maybe His Majesty
ربما جلالته
just remembered the Sheng family
تذكرت للتو عائلة شينغ
and has some instructions.
ويتضمن بعض التعليمات.
This was my mother's dowry back then.
كان هذا مهر والدتي آنذاك.
She always cherished it.
لطالما اعتزت به.
Now, it's yours.
الآن، أصبح ملكك.
Consider it as the Xie family's betrothal gift.
اعتبرها هدية خطوبة من عائلة شي.
Look good?
هل تبدو جيداً؟
Yes.
نعم.
This is my betrothal gift.
هذه هدية خطوبتي.
Grand Tutor Xie, this time,
المعلم الكبير شيه، هذه المرة،
you won't be able to escape.
لن تتمكن من الهرب.
No matter how long you go,
مهما طالت رحلتك،
or if the gates are closed,
أو إذا كانت البوابات مغلقة،
I'll be waiting for you.
سأنتظرك.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Sister.
أخت.
Tell me.
أخبرني.
Why do people live?
لماذا يعيش الناس؟
Sister,
أخت،
Your Majesty,
جلالتك،
why do you say that?
لماذا تقول ذلك؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف.
Looking at you,
بالنظر إليك،
I truly miss my sister.
أشتاق لأختي كثيراً.
How about this?
ما رأيك بهذا؟
You'll compose a poem
سوف تقوم بتأليف قصيدة
for your own sister.
لأجل أختك.
Your Majesty, please speak plainly.
جلالتكم، تفضلوا بالتحدث بوضوح.
Why speak in riddles with me?
لماذا تتحدث معي بالألغاز؟
Right now, a document written by the Grand Princess
في الوقت الحالي، وثيقة كتبتها الأميرة الكبرى
should be reaching Grand Tutor Xie.
ينبغي أن يصل إلى المعلم الكبير شيه.
Write another letter
اكتب رسالة أخرى
in the Grand Princess's hand.
في يد الأميرة الكبرى.
And in her name,
وباسمها،
accuse the Xie family of colluding, harming loyal subjects,
اتهام عائلة شي بالتواطؤ وإلحاق الأذى بالرعايا المخلصين.
and killing the Grand Princess.
وقتل الأميرة الكبرى.
They bear responsibility for the Weiyang Palace incident.
يتحملون مسؤولية حادثة قصر وييانغ.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
(Grand Princess's Letter)
(رسالة الأميرة الكبرى)
Are you saying
هل تقول
this letter
هذه الرسالة
was left by the Grand Princess before her death?
هل تركتها الأميرة الكبرى قبل وفاتها؟
It claims I colluded with Chancellor Huo
يزعمون أنني تواطأت مع المستشار هوو
to kill the Grand Princess.
لقتل الأميرة الكبرى.
I only deliver it.
أنا فقط أقوم بتوصيلها.
I know nothing else.
لا أعرف شيئاً آخر.
But His Majesty said
لكن جلالته قال
you are clever.
أنت ذكي.
You'll understand what this letter implies.
ستفهم ما تعنيه هذه الرسالة.
Back then, this secretary in my sister's palace
في ذلك الوقت، كانت هذه السكرتيرة في قصر أختي
copied my sister's excellent handwriting.
قلدت خط أختي الممتاز.
She usually skipped
كانت تتغيب عادةً
the routine memorials
النصب التذكارية الروتينية
and had him draft responses.
وطلب منه صياغة الردود.
But only Grand Tutor Xie's memorials
لكن فقط نصب تذكارية للمعلم الأكبر شيه
did she handle personally.
هل تعاملت مع الأمر شخصياً؟
Unless my sister comes alive
إلا إذا عادت أختي إلى الحياة
and personally denies writing this secret letter,
وينفي شخصياً كتابة هذه الرسالة السرية،
Grand Tutor Xie's crime
جريمة المعلم الكبير شي
can't be cleared.
لا يمكن مسحها.
Your Majesty, don't act impulsively
يا صاحب الجلالة، لا تتصرف باندفاع.
and hurt a loyal minister.
وألحق الضرر بوزير مخلص.
Won't you admit who you really are?
ألن تعترف بمن أنت حقاً؟
Sister,
أخت،
Xie Fei could be sentenced to death this time.
قد يُحكم على شي فاي بالإعدام هذه المرة.
Your Majesty,
جلالتك،
if Grand Tutor Xie is convicted,
في حال إدانة المعلم الأكبر شي،
I'll follow him in life or death.
سأتبعه في الحياة أو الموت.
There's another way to exonerate Grand Tutor Xie.
هناك طريقة أخرى لتبرئة المعلم الأكبر شيه.
I also have deep ties with the Sheng family from Yunnan.
كما تربطني علاقات وثيقة بعائلة شينغ من يونان.
If you change your mind now
إذا غيرت رأيك الآن
and marry me in the palace,
وتزوجني في القصر،
this joyful union between families
هذا الاتحاد السعيد بين العائلات
could warrant a general pardon.
قد يستدعي ذلك عفواً عاماً.
You're insane!
أنت مجنون!
Yes.
نعم.
I am insane.
أنا مجنون.
I've gone mad.
لقد جننت.
Only madness explains how you all
الجنون وحده يفسر كيف حالكم جميعاً
could manipulate me so easily.
كان بإمكانه التلاعب بي بسهولة بالغة.
Even now,
وحتى الآن،
I'm still speaking calmly to you.
ما زلت أتحدث إليك بهدوء.
Instead of deposing the empress and marrying you outright.
بدلاً من خلع الإمبراطورة والزواج منكِ مباشرةً.
I'm still afraid of frightening you.
ما زلت أخشى أن أخيفك.
No.
لا.
Not mad enough.
ليس غاضباً بما فيه الكفاية.
I'm not mad enough yet.
لم أغضب بما فيه الكفاية بعد.
- Your Majesty! - Sister, don't push me away.
- جلالتك! - أختي، لا تدفعيني بعيداً.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
I trapped you
لقد أوقعتك في الفخ
in Weiyang Palace.
في قصر وييانغ.
I gave them the opportunity.
لقد منحتهم الفرصة.
Back in court,
العودة إلى المحكمة،
I echoed their arguments.
رددت حججهم.
I only wanted to find a scapegoat for you.
أردت فقط أن أجد لك كبش فداء.
I can bring you into the harem.
بإمكاني إدخالك إلى الحريم.
I can give you a new identity.
أستطيع أن أمنحك هوية جديدة.
I can make you completely mine.
أستطيع أن أجعلك ملكي بالكامل.
Sheng Yunlin,
شنغ يونلين،
I was the first to fall for you.
كنت أول من وقع في حبك.
I was the one who stayed by your side all along.
كنت أنا من بقي بجانبك طوال الوقت.
You promised you'd always stay with me.
لقد وعدتني بأنك ستبقى معي دائماً.
Why won't you acknowledge me now?
لماذا لا تعترف بوجودي الآن؟
Your Majesty,
جلالتك،
Grand Tutor Xie said,
قال المعلم الكبير شيه:
he wishes to bear all guilt alone,
يرغب في تحمل كل الذنب وحده،
- not implicating his family. - Get lost!
- عدم توريط عائلته. - ارحل!
Sister.
أخت.
Your thoughts are truly unfathomable today.
أفكارك اليوم غامضة حقاً.
If you insist on persisting in folly,
إذا أصررت على الاستمرار في الحماقة،
I refuse to let my husband suffer this unjust calamity.
أرفض أن يعاني زوجي من هذه المصيبة الظالمة.
I will follow him in death.
سألحق به في الموت.
You'd rather die for that man
ستفضل الموت من أجل ذلك الرجل
than acknowledge me?
بدلاً من الاعتراف بي؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
If I were her,
لو كنت مكانها،
would you have ever pitied me
هل كنت ستشفق عليّ يوماً؟
for dying once for the Chen State?
هل من أجل الموت مرة واحدة من أجل ولاية تشين؟
If I were not her,
لو لم أكن هي،
why must you obsess over me,
لماذا يجب أن تهتم بي كثيراً؟
neglect state affairs, and become a tyrant?
إهمال شؤون الدولة، والتحول إلى طاغية؟
But I don't want to be sovereign.
لكنني لا أريد أن أكون صاحب السيادة.
I just want you.
أريدك أنت فقط.
Your Majesty is a wise ruler.
جلالتكم حاكم حكيم.
Your sister
أختك
is watching over you.
هو يراقبك.
Let this be you
أتمنى أن تكون أنت هذا الشخص
seeing me off one last time.
وداعاً لي للمرة الأخيرة.
His Majesty is critically ill. The palace is on lockdown.
جلالته في حالة حرجة. القصر مغلق.
No one enters without summons.
لا يُسمح لأحد بالدخول بدون استدعاء.
Seal the palace gates! Now!
أغلقوا أبواب القصر! الآن!
(Yu.)
(يو.)
Go.
يذهب.
Your Majesty,
جلالتك،
we've been married for long.
لقد تزوجنا منذ فترة طويلة.
Why does seeing me
لماذا رؤيتي
make you so bashful?
يجعلك هذا خجولاً للغاية؟
Viper.
فايبر.
Viper?
أفعى؟
Your Majesty, have you ever considered
جلالة الملك، هل فكرتم يوماً في
who turned me into what I am today?
من الذي جعلني ما أنا عليه اليوم؟
I was also once a noble lady famed throughout the capital.
كنتُ أيضاً في يوم من الأيام سيدة نبيلة مشهورة في جميع أنحاء العاصمة.
In my youth, I fell for you at first sight.
في شبابي، وقعت في حبك من النظرة الأولى.
Do you know
هل تعلم
how overjoyed I was when I learned
كم كنت سعيداً عندما علمت
I could marry you?
هل يمكنني الزواج بك؟
Yet on our very wedding night,
لكن في ليلة زفافنا،
to seize control of the Imperial Guard,
للاستيلاء على السيطرة على الحرس الإمبراطوري،
you schemed and murdered my own brother!
لقد تآمرت وقتلت أخي!
Though I am the Empress,
مع أنني الإمبراطورة،
all authority
جميع السلطات
was handed entirely to the Grand Princess.
تم تسليمها بالكامل إلى الأميرة الكبرى.
My father used me as a pawn.
استخدمني والدي كأداة.
Even you did the same.
حتى أنت فعلت الشيء نفسه.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
In your heart,
في قلبك،
was there ever a single moment
هل كانت هناك لحظة واحدة على الأقل
where there was me?
أين كنتُ؟
You...
أنت...
As long as you nod
طالما أنك أومأت برأسك
and say yes,
وقل نعم،
I can...
أنا استطيع...
I can spare your life.
بإمكاني أن أنقذ حياتك.
Nod.
أومأ برأسه.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Nod!
أومئ برأسك!
Say yes!
قل نعم!
(Sheng Yunlin,)
(شنغ يونلين،)
(everything you once possessed,)
(كل ما كنت تملكه في السابق،)
(now belongs to me.)
(أصبحت ملكي الآن.)
(I will stand higher than you ever did,)
(سأكون أعلى مما كنت عليه طوال حياتك،)
(looking down upon all.)
(ينظر إلى الجميع بازدراء.)
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
the harem must stay out.
يجب أن يبقى الحريم بالخارج.
How can you usurp authority?
كيف يمكنك اغتصاب السلطة؟
Much less sit upon the Dragon Throne.
ناهيك عن الجلوس على عرش التنين.
This violates the rules of Chen State.
هذا ينتهك قواعد ولاية تشين.
Indeed.
بالفعل.
When the Grand Princess acted as regent, it was by His Majesty's decree.
عندما تولت الأميرة الكبرى منصب الوصية، كان ذلك بموجب مرسوم من جلالة الملك.
Now, you lack
الآن، أنت تفتقر
any legitimate authority!
أي سلطة شرعية!
My actions today
أفعالي اليوم
are ordained by Heaven.
هي مُقَدَّرة من السماء.
To voice dissatisfaction
للتعبير عن الاستياء
is to defy Heaven's will.
هو تحدّي إرادة السماء.
Heaven's way is clear.
طريق السماء واضح.
Gentlemen,
السادة المحترمون،
be cautious.
كن حذرا.
- We are at your command.
- نحن تحت أمرك.
State your business.
حدد نشاطك التجاري.
Jinxiu.
جينكسيو.
Earlier in the court,
في وقت سابق في المحكمة،
do I look imposing?
هل أبدو مهيباً؟
You have finally reached this point.
لقد وصلت أخيرًا إلى هذه المرحلة.
I am overjoyed for you.
أنا سعيد للغاية من أجلك.
Throughout the land,
في جميع أنحاء البلاد،
no one dares question you anymore.
لم يعد أحد يجرؤ على التشكيك بك.
Come.
يأتي.
Only you...
أنت فقط...
Only you truly rejoice for me from the heart.
أنت وحدك من تفرح لي من صميم قلبك.
Having you by my side
وجودك بجانبي
is truly wonderful.
إنه لأمر رائع حقاً.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
you have treated me so kindly.
لقد عاملتني بلطف شديد.
You have never punished me.
لم تعاقبني قط.
Since following you in my youth,
منذ أن كنت أتابعك في شبابي،
I've known warm clothes in winter,
أعرف الملابس الدافئة في الشتاء،
and ice in summer cellar storage.
والثلج في تخزين القبو خلال فصل الصيف.
If there is a next life,
إذا كانت هناك حياة أخرى،
I will still serve you.
سأظل أخدمك.
Good.
جيد.
However, these old ministers
لكن هؤلاء الوزراء القدامى
are masters of paying lip service
هم بارعون في التظاهر بالولاء.
and standing by idly.
والوقوف مكتوفي الأيدي.
Jinxiu,
جينكسيو،
go help me keep an eye
اذهب وساعدني في مراقبة المكان
on their families detained in the palace.
بشأن عائلاتهم المحتجزة في القصر.
If anyone causes trouble,
إذا تسبب أي شخص في حدوث مشكلة،
show no mercy.
لا ترحم.
Yes.
نعم.
♪The wind rises, snow falls♪
تهبّ الرياح، ويتساقط الثلج.
♪To stain endless remorse with red♪
لصبغ الندم الذي لا ينتهي باللون الأحمر؟
♪No regrets in moves made. Let the game unfold♪
لا ندم على أي خطوة. دع اللعبة تسير كما هي.
♪Sorrow and joy intertwined♪
???الحزن والفرح متشابكان؟؟؟
♪Yet we can't escape karma♪
ومع ذلك، لا يمكننا الهروب من الكارما.
♪Lament this fleeting life♪
???أحزن على هذه الحياة الزائلة؟؟؟
♪So elusive♪
???صعب المنال للغاية؟؟؟
♪So indistinct♪
غير واضح للغاية؟
♪Resent farewells♪
???وداعات مؤلمة؟؟؟
♪Remembering each other♪
نتذكر بعضنا البعض
♪Love can't be extinguished♪
الحب لا يمكن إخماده.
♪Unwilling to accept♪
غير راغب في القبول؟
♪Rewriting the story♪
إعادة كتابة القصة
♪And praying♪
والصلاة؟
♪A long-cherished wish♪
أمنية طالما تمنّيناها
♪In a daze♪
في حالة ذهول
♪Suddenly it's those years again♪
فجأةً، عادت تلك السنوات من جديد!
♪How I wish to relive my old dreams♪
كم أتمنى أن أعيش أحلامي القديمة من جديد!
♪Rewrite those torn pages♪
أعد كتابة تلك الصفحات الممزقة!